Guide to the Records of National Conference on Soviet Jewry, undated, 1949, 1954, 1956, 1958-1993 *I-181 and *I-181A
American Jewish Historical Society, Newton Centre, MA and New York, NY
- Part 2, Series I: NCSJ Administrative Records, undated, 1965-1966, 1970-1993; Boxes 1-21.
  - Subseries A: Staff Member Files and General Records, undated, 1965-1966, 1970-1990; Boxes 1-9.
    - Goodman, Jerry -- Executive director correspondence, January-October 1984 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Goodman, Jerry -- Executive director correspondence, November 1984-March 1985 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Goodman, Jerry -- Executive director correspondence, April-August 1985 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Goodman, Jerry -- Executive director correspondence, August-September 1985 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Goodman, Jerry -- Executive director correspondence, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Goodman, Jerry -- Executive director correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Goodman, Jerry -- correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Wenick, Martin E. -- Executive director's correspondence, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Wenick, Martin E. -- Executive director's correspondence, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Levinson, Burton S. -- Chairman's correspondence, 1979-1982 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Mann, Theodore -- Chairman's correspondence, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Mann, Theodore -- Chairman's correspondence, 1982-1984 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Abram, Morris B. -- Chairman's correspondence, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Abram, Morris B. -- Chairman's correspondence, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Abram, Morris B. -- Chairman's correspondence, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Abram, Morris B. -- Chairman's correspondence, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Abram, Morris B. -- Chairman's correspondence, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Abram, Morris B. -- Chairman's calendar, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Abram, Morris B. -- Chairman's correspondence, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Abram, Morris B. -- Chairman's correspondence, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Speeches, undated, 1966, 1979-1982, 1984-1985, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Cardin, Shoshana -- Chairman's correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Cardin, Shoshana -- Chairman's correspondence, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Shinbaum, Myrna -- Associate director's correspondence, 1979-1986 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Shinbaum, Myrna -- Associate director's correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Shinbaum, Myrna -- Memoranda and information, 1987-1989 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Shinbaum, Myrna -- Publications on Soviet Jewry, 1965, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Shinbaum, Myrna -- Publications on Soviet Jewry, 1971-1990 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Gold, Eugene, undated, 1977-1983 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Lowell, Stanley, 1980-1982, 1984-1987 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Maass, Richard, 1978, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Valk, Elie, undated, 1979-1981 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - National and Regional Staff Member Meeting, November 8, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Resumes, 1982-1984 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Resumes, 1985-1987 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Subseries B: Board of Governors, 1978-1986, 1988-1989; Boxes 10-11.
    - Records, 1978-1980 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Mailings, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Mailings, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Records, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Records, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Records, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Records, 1985-1986 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Strategy session, January 13, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Meeting, February 10, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Meeting, June 7, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Meeting, June 16, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Meeting, September 22, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Records, 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Subseries C: Executive Committee, undated, 1972-1989; Boxes 12-13.
    - Records, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Records, 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1975-August 1976 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, September-December 1976 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Records, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Records, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Records, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Records, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Meeting, December 7, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Meeting, April 4, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Meeting, June 9, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Meeting, October 22, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Meeting, January 21, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Meeting, September 21, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Meeting, October 22, October 30, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Records, 1985-1988 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Records, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Bios and photos, undated, 1983-1985 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Subseries D: Additional Committees and Divisions, undated, 1974-1989; Boxes 14-16.
    - Activities and Advocacy on Behalf of Soviet Jewry, 1982, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Administrative and Management Committee, 1978-1980 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Advisory Council, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Advisory Task Force, 1985-1986 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Business Advisory Committee, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Business Advisory Committee, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Business Advisory Committee, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Business Advisory Committee, 1977-1983 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Community Relations Committee, 1975, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Council of Associates, 1983-1986 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Crisis committee, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Local Soviet Jewry Chairpersons, 1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Long Range Planning Committee, 1974-1976 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Medical Action Committee, undated, 1986-1988 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Memos and correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Olympic Advisory Committee (Moscow 1980), 1978-1980 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Plenary Meetings, 1975-1976 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Policy Advisory Committee, 1985-1986 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Political Action Committee, undated, 1982, 1984-1985 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Resolutions by Communities and Organizations on Soviet Jewry, undated, 1974, 1976-1979, 1980-1981, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Review Committee, undated, 1980-1981 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Review Task Force Members, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Review Task Force Committee, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Review Task Force Committee, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Review Task Force Committee, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Strategic Assessment Task Force, 1986-1987 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Washington Office, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Washington Office, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Washington Office, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Washington Office, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Washington Office, 1982-1984 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Washington Office, 1985-1989 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Subseries E: National Jewish Community Relations Advisory Council (NJCRAC), undated, 1972, 1974-1993; Boxes 17-21.
    - NJCRAC Conference, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Executive meeting, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Interfaith Committee, undated, 1976-1977, 1983-1989, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Israel Task Force, 1988-1989 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Joint Distribution Committee, 1985-1986 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Joint Distribution Committee, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Joint Distribution Committee, 1988-1989 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Joint Program Plan, 1976, 1979, 1984, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Joint Program Plan, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Joint Program Plan, 1990-1991 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Lebanon, 1976, 1978-1981 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Lebanon, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Lebanon, 1983-1986, 1989, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - McDonnell, Tom, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - McElroy, Mary, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Media Watch Report, 1989-1990 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Memos, 1972, 1974-1978 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Memos, January-February 1979 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Memos, March-June 1979 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Memos, July-December 1979 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Memos, January-April 1980 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Memos, May-September 1980 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Memos, October-December 1980 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Memos, 1981-1986 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Memos, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Memos, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Memos, January-March 1989 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Memos, April-June 1989 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Memos, July-December 1989 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Memos, January-June 1990 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Memos, July-December 1990 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Memos, January-June 1991 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Memos, July 1991-1992 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - NCSJ Activities, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Nominating Committee, 1972, 1980, 1985-1988 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Nominating Committee, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Plenum, 1990-1991 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Yom Hashoah, 1983, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Yom Hashoah, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 8)
- Part 2, Series II: Public Relations Records, undated, 1971-1991; Boxes 22-29.
  The Series reflects the public relations effort of the NCSJ and includes the bulletin NCSJ in the Media (1977-1987), files on persons who cooperated with NCSJ on publicity issues (Jane Fonda, Elie Wiesel, Armand Hammer, Elmer Winter, Guilford Glazer), and Press Releases covering the activities of the organization from 1971 through 1986. Also included are press advertisements, letters to editors, and materials on broadcasts featured on Radio Maccabi. The Series is divided into two Subseries, Publicity Records, 1976-1991 and Press Releases, undated, 1971-1987.
  - Subseries A: Publicity Records, 1976-1991; Box 22-Box 24, Folder 8.
    - 1985 Year End Press Event, January 2, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Advertisement-Contributors, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Armand Hammer Materials, 1979-1987 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Board for International Broadcasting, 1985-1988 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Cancelled Media Panel on Refuseniks, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Elie Wiesel Materials, 1979-1987 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Elmer Winter Materials, 1985-1989 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Glazer, Guilford, 1976-1977 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Glazer, Guilford, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Glazer, Guilford, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Glazer, Guilford, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Glazer, Guilford, 1981 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Glazer, Guilford, 1982-1984 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Glazer, Guilford, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Glazer, Guilford, 1986-1987, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Information Materials, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Jane Fonda Materials, 1982, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Media Materials, 1985-1990 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Media: NCSJ Letters to Editors, 1981, 1983-1985 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - NCSJ in the Media, 1977-1978 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - NCSJ in the Media, 1982-1983 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - NCSJ in the Media, 1984-1985 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - NCSJ in the Media, undated, 1986-1987 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - NCSJ Press Kit, 1991 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - New York Times Advertising "Window of Opportunity", October 27, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Phil Donahue Talk Show, February 1987 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Subseries B: Press Releases, undated, 1971-1987; Box 24, Folder 9 -- Box 29.
    - Press Releases, January 1971-January 1972 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Press Releases, February 1972-August 1972 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Press Releases, September 1972-February 1973 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Press Releases, March 1973-October 1973 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Press Releases, November 1973-April 1974 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Press Releases, May 1974-December 1974 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Press Releases, January 1975-July 1975 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Press Releases, August 1975-December 1975 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Press Releases with Photos, January 1976-May 1976 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Press Releases with Photos, June 1976-September 1976 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Press Releases with Photos, October 1976-December 1976 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Press Releases with Photos, January 1977-March 1977 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Press Releases with Photos, April 1977-June 1977 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Press Releases with Photos, July 1977-December 1977 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Press Releases with Photos including KGB shadowing refuseniks, January 1978-April 1978 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Press Releases, May 1978-June 1978 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Press Releases, July 1978-December 1978 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Press Releases with Photo, January 1979-May 1979 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Press Releases, June 1979-December 1979 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Press Releases, January 1980-June 1980 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Press Releases, July 1980-December 1980 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Press Releases, January 1981-June 1981 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Press Releases, July 1981-December 1981 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Press Releases, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Press Releases, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Press Releases, 1985 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Press Releases, February 1986-September 1986 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Press Releases, October 1986-December 1986 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Public Information Officer (J. Schenker), 1976 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Radio Maccabee, undated, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Radio Moscow, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Richard Cohen's Jerusalem Press File, undated, 1981-1983 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Sixty Minutes -- "Soviet Jewry", March 22, 1987 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Soviet Jewry Research Bureau, 1975-1982 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Voice of America, 1979-1986 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Washington Post Ad "Secretary Shcherbitskiy and Visiting Soviet Parlamentarians", March 5, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 8)
- Part 2, Series III: Fundraising Records, undated, 1976-1987; Boxes 30-34.
  The Series contains materials related to the fundraising efforts of NCSJ, an includes projects, proposals and appeals on fundraising and development, Large City Budgeting Conference (LCBC) materials, corporate and foundation contacts, lists of individuals, religious groups and schools.
  - Computers, 1982-1983 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Computers, undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Corporations -- A-E, undated, 1981-1982 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Corporations -- F-X, 1980-1982 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Developers -- Biographical data forms, undated, 1982-1983 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Foundations -- General, A-F, undated, 1982-1983 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Foundations -- General, G-N, undated, 1981-1982 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Foundations -- General, P-R, undated, 1981-1982 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Foundations -- not appropriate, C-K, undated, 1981-1983 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Foundations -- not appropriate, M-W, 1981-1982 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Foundations -- questionnaire, undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Foundations Research, undated, 1986 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Fundraising appeals -- Jewish, 1979-1983 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Fundraising appeals -- Jewish, undated (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Fundraising appeals -- miscellaneous, undated, 1977, 1979-1983 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Fundraising resources, 1986 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Funding project proposals, undated, 1977, 1979-1984 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Fundraising effort, 1980, 1983-1986 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - General Information on Fundraising Resources, undated, 1982-1984 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Individuals, 1976-1978 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Individuals, 1979-1980 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Individuals, 1981-1982 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Jewish Foundations, undated, 1977-1984 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Kamber Group, undated, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Large City Budgeting Conference/Councils of Jewish Federations, 1980-1985 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Large City Budgeting Conference Activities Report on NCSJ, 1976 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Mellon Bank Good Neighbor Award, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - NCSJ Advisory Council Strategy, undated, 1979-1984 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - NCSJ Advisory Council: Prospects, undated, 1979-1982 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - NCSJ Council of Associates, undated, 1983-1984 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Newsletters, 1983 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Pharmaceutical Company Solicitations, 1987 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Prospects -- Individuals, undated, 1978-1983 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Prospects -- Corporations, undated, 1980-1982 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Prospects -- Former Executive Committee Members, undated, 1978-1982 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Prospects -- United Jewish Appeal, Young Leadership, undated, 1983 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Reference -- Other Human Rights-International and Domestic, 1981-1983 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Religious groups and schools, 1977-1979 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Religious groups and schools, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Religious groups and schools, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Religious groups and schools, 1982 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Synagogues, undated, 1979, 1982-1983 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Unsolicited Individual Donations, 1982-1983 (Box 34, Folder 13)
- Part 2, Series IV: Conferences, Actions, Projects and Events, undated, 1966-1991; Boxes 35-53.
  The Series covers the activities of the NCSJ that attracted both Jewish and non-Jewish supporters and raised awareness in the American public on the plight of Soviet Jewry. The organization of projects and the holding of events on behalf of Soviet refuseniks and prisoners of conscience were, along with the lobbying efforts on behalf of, Soviet Jewish issues within seats of power in the U.S.-the most important and the most popular kind of activities-enhanced public visibility of the NCSJ efforts and allowed individual American Jews and their families to join in particular projects that broadened the strength and support base of the Movement.
  Among the projects were Pen Pals, Bar/Bat Mitzvah Twinning, Adopt-a-Family, International Day of Concern for Soviet Jews, and consultations and meetings with prominent activists and politicians. NCSJ contacted former refuseniks and prisoners of conscience to enlist them in the effort of spreading information about the repressions against Jews in the Soviet Union, and organized their trips and lectures. Within the "Mishlakhat" project, relatives of prisoners of conscience toured Jewish communities- speaking out on the life conditions of Jews in the Soviet Union-and campaigning for the release of their imprisoned loved ones.
  Some Bar/Bat Mitzvah folders contain photographs of Soviet Jewish children and their families, as well as their American counterparts-children, whose Bar or Bat Mitzvah ceremony included a symbolic presence of the Soviet Jewish child, deprived in his or her homeland of the right to celebrate the assumption of Jewish religious responsibilities.
  Correspondence with families of refuseniks and prisoners of conscience within the Pen Pal and Adopt-a-Family programs was an important avenue of contacts with Soviet Jews, providing moral support and often, material help from American pen pals, as well as updated information on the status and condition of the refuseniks, prisoners and Jews in general in a given locality of the Soviet Union.
  The Series is divided into two Subseries: Projects, 1972-1976, 1978-1989, 1991 and Events, undated, 1966, 1971, 1974-1989.
  - Subseries A: Projects, undated, 1972-1976, 1978-1989, 1991; Boxes 35-40.
    - Babi Yar War Memorial, 1991 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Bar and Bat Mitzvah Twinning -- project information, 1981-1983 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Bar and Bat Mitzvah Twinning -- Lists, 1982 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Bar and Bat Mitzvah Twinning -- Lists, undated, 1983-1984 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Bar and Bat Mitzvah Twinning -- families information, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Bar and Bat Mitzvah Twinning -- project information, undated, 1985-1989 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Bar and Bat Mitzvah Twinning -- Correspondence, 1980, 1982, 1984-1985 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Bar and Bat Mitzvah Twinning -- Instructional Materials, undated, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Bar and Bat Mitzvah Twinning -- Invitations and Certificates, undated, 1978, 1981, 1983-1984 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Bar and Bat Mitzvah Twinning -- Memos and Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Bar and Bat Mitzvah Twinning -- Memos and Correspondence, 1984 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Bar and Bat Mitzvah Twinning -- News Clippings and Brochures, undated, 1980-1983 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Bar and Bat Mitzvah Twinning Twin -- Profiles, Printed Material Orders, undated (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - "Candle in the Wind," film by Pacem Productions Inc., 1983-1987 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - "Candle in the Wind," film script, 1984 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Community Refusenik Adoptions, undated, 1985 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Corporate Contacts, 1987-1988 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Corporate Sensitivity Project, 1972-1973, 1978 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Corporate Sensitivity Project, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Corporate Sensitivity Project, 1983-1985 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Corporate Sensitivity Project, January 1986-August 1986 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Corporate Sensitivity Project, September 1986-December 1986 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Corporate Sensitivity Project, 1987 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Corporate Sensitivity Project, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Forest of Posters Project, 1982 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Former POC Visits, 1978, 1982 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - International Petition Campaign with Photos, undated, 1981-1982, 1986-1987 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Iosif Begun: Book by J. Singer, The Case of Iosif Begun: Analysis & Documents, Tel Aviv, 1979 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Iosif Begun -- Hebrew Teaching, 1978, 1983 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Iosif Begun -- Hebrew Teaching-UNESCO, 1979, 1983 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Kamber Group, undated, 1986 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Lawsuit against Intourist, undated, 1983, 1986 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Lowenstein International Human Rights Law Project, 1984, 1986-1987, 1990 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Mailing Profiles, 1975-1976 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Matzah of Hope, 1986 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Michlachat (Relatives of POC's meetings), undated, 1979 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Nation-Wide Petition Campaign, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - NCSJ Calendars, 1987 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Operation Lifeline, undated, 1980-1983, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Operation Soviet Jewry Write-In, undated (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Penpals Project, 1989 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Petition Campaign (contains photograph), 1981 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Petition Campaign, 1982 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Phone Calls to USSR, undated, 1973-1975 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - "Priority POC" Project, 1987 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Project "Sefer", undated, 1978-1983 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Project Write-On, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Projects and Proposals, 1979-1981, 1984-1985 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Refusenik Roll Call Campaign, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Runs for Soviet Jewry, 1980-1981 (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Solomon Mikhoels Cultural Center, 1989 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Solomon Mikhoels Cultural Center -- Publications, 1989 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Soviet Jewry Ad Campaign, 1982 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Soviet Jewry Forest (Jewish National Fund), 1982-1983 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Soviet Jewry Petition Drive, 1985 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Telegrams to USSR Foreign Minister Gromyko at Soviet Mission to UN, 1981-1982 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - The Record Publication and Congressional Mailings, 1980 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Women's Plea for Soviet Jewry, 1987-1989 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Subseries B: Events, undated, 1966, 1971, 1974-1989; Boxes 41-53.
    - Abram, M. and Bronfman, E. Visit to Moscow, 1987 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Brezhnev's Pardon of Five Prisoners of Conscience, April 1979 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Brotherhood Week, 1980 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Cancelled Leadership Training Seminar, Israel, November 1980 (Box 41, Folder 4)